Pedram Khoshnevis

Pedramkhoshnevis@gmail.com

+1-306-580-3888

https://www.linkedin.com/in/pedramkhoshnevis

SUMMARY

I have 10 years of programming experience and during this time, I have developed countless programs to solve any challenging problem that I have faced. I am team-oriented, detail-oriented, fast learner and in regards to programs developed, I pay special attention to ensure that security, integrity, and efficiencies are maintained. My previous work experience has given me knowledge of the proper object-oriented programming practices and the proper usage of synchronous and asynchronous functions. I have experience working with SQL, NoSQL databases, scripting languages, following the Application Programming Interface (API) manuals, using transaction and isolation levels in database systems. My studies in Computer Science with a Minor in Management has familiarized me with Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) systems, Project Management, and Business Analysis. I have an excellent overall working knowledge of all aspects of computers and Information Technology (IT). This includes software, hardware, networking, distributed systems, and desktop support.

EDUCATION

University of Seoul

Mar 2013 - Mar 2015

M.S. Computer Science, Computer Networking.

Thesis Title: An Adaptive Distance-Based Network Coding Protocol for Unreliable Wireless Networks.

Honors in General Scholarship. GPA 95%.

Publication: An Adaptive Network Coding scheme for unreliable multi-hop wireless networks.

Universiti Sains Malaysia

Mar 2007 - Mar 2011

B.S. Computer Science, Distributed Systems and Network Security.

Minor: Management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Programming Experience – Full-Stack Developer. Fluent in PHP (Laravel), JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Hybrid Phone apps (React-native, Ionic, PhoneGap), Server programming (LAMP setup and Linux commands), Responsive design, jQuery, Creating Rest-Full API, AWS EC2, Route 53, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Elasticsearch, Git version control, Relational databases MySQL (transactions and isolation levels) and NoSQL database Mongo dB, Database ORM, MVC Architecture, Business essentials ACL (access control list), phpMyAdmin, Sessions (Redis, Memcached), Socket.io, Synchronous and asynchronous programming, Database migration and seeding, Public and Private key (SSL), Password protection (hash, salt, pepper), Security (CSRF tokens, Cookie encryption and decryption, Sessions), Familiar with Python, C++ and C.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

• University of Regina (Biology-Ecology Laboratory) – Regina, Canada

Apr 2018 – Sep 2018

• Apposha.io – SK Planet, Seoul, South Korea

Jul 2017 – Apr 2018

• FantaPlan – Hongdae, Seoul, South Korea

Apr 2015 - Apr 2016

Eyelevate – Gangnam, Seoul, South Korea Mar 2014 – Mar 2015

Worked as a Junior Web Developer at Eyelevate. My role was to develop mobile responsive web applications using the MVC framework (PHP/Laravel). I also used Git as a version-control software and Integrated applications with various APIs. I developed my application using Linux, Apache, MySQL, and PHP (LAMP Stack) on the server-side and HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript on the client-side. During my work at FantaPlan and Apposha.io, I developed an application similar to Amazon Web Services (AWS) to provide a database as a service tool. I developed a Content Management System (CMS) to accommodate such tools. This gave me experience in using AWS tools such as Elastic Beanstalk, Elasticsearch, CloudFormation, and Route53.